http://www.ilcc.cc.ia.us/privacy-policy/

future students
Start Here!
Virtual Tours
Visit Us!
future students
Start Here!
Apply for Housing
Apply for Housing (International)
Housing Video Tours
StarNet River Valley Internet Service Report Form - Estherville Campus
Online Programs
How Do Online Courses Work?
Spirit Lake Campus
Visit Us!
Adult Education & Literacy Program
High School Equivalency Instruction (English and Spanish)
English as a Second Language (ESL)
Refund of Tuition
Visit Us!
Individual Visit
Laker Visit Days
Group Visits
Anonymous Reporting Link/Sexual Violence Procedures
I was recently sexually assaulted! What do I do?
Where can I go for help?
Who will see the report?
Why is an anonymous report beneficial?
What if I was sexually assaulted a long time ago?
Apply for Housing
Apply for Housing (International)
Housing Video Tours
StarNet River Valley Internet Service Report Form - Estherville Campus
Anonymous Reporting Link/Sexual Violence Procedures
I was recently sexually assaulted! What do I do?
Where can I go for help?
Who will see the report?
Why is an anonymous report beneficial?
What if I was sexually assaulted a long time ago?
Online Programs
How Do Online Courses Work?
Apply for Housing
Apply for Housing (International)
Housing Video Tours
StarNet River Valley Internet Service Report Form - Estherville Campus
Anonymous Reporting Link/Sexual Violence Procedures
I was recently sexually assaulted! What do I do?
Where can I go for help?
Who will see the report?
Why is an anonymous report beneficial?
What if I was sexually assaulted a long time ago?
Apply for Housing
Apply for Housing (International)
Housing Video Tours
StarNet River Valley Internet Service Report Form - Estherville Campus
Anonymous Reporting Link/Sexual Violence Procedures
I was recently sexually assaulted! What do I do?
Where can I go for help?
Who will see the report?
Why is an anonymous report beneficial?
What if I was sexually assaulted a long time ago?
Apply for Housing
Apply for Housing (International)
Housing Video Tours
StarNet River Valley Internet Service Report Form - Estherville Campus
Winterim Term
Degree Audit (Academic Evaluation)
Referral Process
Referral Check List (Special Education Teacher Only)
Anonymous Reporting Link/Sexual Violence Procedures
I was recently sexually assaulted! What do I do?
Where can I go for help?
Who will see the report?
Why is an anonymous report beneficial?
What if I was sexually assaulted a long time ago?
Adult Education & Literacy Program
High School Equivalency Instruction (English and Spanish)
English as a Second Language (ESL)
Refund of Tuition
Visit Us!
Winterim Term
Degree Audit (Academic Evaluation)
Apply for Housing
Apply for Housing (International)
Housing Video Tours
StarNet River Valley Internet Service Report Form - Estherville Campus
Anonymous Reporting Link/Sexual Violence Procedures
I was recently sexually assaulted! What do I do?
Where can I go for help?
Who will see the report?
Why is an anonymous report beneficial?
What if I was sexually assaulted a long time ago?
Apply for Housing
Apply for Housing (International)
Housing Video Tours
StarNet River Valley Internet Service Report Form - Estherville Campus
Anonymous Reporting Link/Sexual Violence Procedures
I was recently sexually assaulted! What do I do?
Where can I go for help?
Who will see the report?
Why is an anonymous report beneficial?
What if I was sexually assaulted a long time ago?
Apply for Housing
Apply for Housing (International)
Housing Video Tours
StarNet River Valley Internet Service Report Form - Estherville Campus
Winterim Term
Degree Audit (Academic Evaluation)
Referral Process
Referral Check List (Special Education Teacher Only)
contact us
Enter criteria to search for:
Overview
Thank you for visiting the Iowa Lakes Community College website and reviewing our privacy statement. Your privacy is very important to us. Iowa Lakes does not collect personal information about visitors to our website unless you choose to provide that information to us voluntarily. Iowa Lakes Community College does not sell, exchange or release information gathered from your visit to our website to parties outside the college without your consent. Once we obtain your consent, we consider it valid until revoked by you.
Information Collected and Stored Automatically
When you visit our website, we automatically gather and store the following information about your visit so that we can track the use of our website in order to make improvements. This information is used for internal college statistical purposes only, and is not used to contact you personally:
The IP address from which you access our website
The Internet address of the website from which you linked to this website
The browser version and configuration information used to access our website
The date and time of a visit to a web page
The pages, files, documents and links that you visit
Search terms used on our search engine
Cookies
Iowa Lakes Community College uses only temporary cookies. Cookies are small pieces of information that are stored by the user's browser on the hard drive of your computer. Cookies are also used to provide statistical analysis and to determine what information is of most and least interest to our users.
Linking
Throughout our website, we link to other sites. When linking to third party sites, you are leaving our website and no longer will be subject to our privacy policy. Iowa Lakes is not responsible for the privacy practices or content of third party websites.
Privacy of Records
Iowa Lakes Community College complies with the Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act (FERPA)  of 1974 which affords students certain rights with respect to their education records. They are:
The right to inspect and review the student’s education records within 45 days of the day the college receives a request for access. A student should submit to the director of records and registration/ registrar or other appropriate official a written request that identifies the record(s) the student wishes to inspect. The registrar will make arrangements for access and notify the student of the time and place where the records may be inspected. If the records are not maintained by the registrar, the registrar shall advise the student of the correct official to whom the request should be addressed.
The right to request the amendment of the student’s education records that the student believes are inaccurate or misleading. A student may ask the college to amend a record that the student believes is inaccurate or misleading. The student should write to the college official responsible for the record, clearly identify the part of the record the student wants changed, and specify why it is inaccurate or misleading. (Note: FERPA was not intended to provide a process to be used to question substantive judgments which are correctly recorded. The rights of challenge are not intended to allow a student to contest, for example, a grade in a course because the student felt a higher grade should have been assigned.) If the college decides not to amend the record as requested by the student, the college will notify the student of the decision and advise the student of his or her right to a hearing regarding the request for amendment. Additional information regarding the hearing procedures will be provided to the student when notified of the right to a hearing.
The right to consent to disclosures of personally identifiable information contained the student’s education records, except to the extent that FERPA authorizes disclosure without consent. One exception which permits disclosure without consent is disclosure to college officials with 45 legitimate educational interests. A college official is a person employed by the college in an administrative, supervisory, academic or research or support staff position (including law enforcement unit personnel and health staff, if any); a person or company with whom the college has contacted (such as an attorney, auditor or collection agent); a person serving on the college board of trustees or a student serving on an official committee, such as a discipline or grievance committee, or assisting another college official in performing his or her tasks. A college official has a legitimate educational interest if the official needs to review an education record in order to fulfill his or her professional responsibility. Upon request, the college discloses education records without consent to officials of another school in which a student seeks or intends to enroll.
The right to file a complaint with the U.S. Department of Education concerning alleged failures of Iowa Lakes Community College to comply with the requirements of FERPA. The name and address of the office that administers FERPA is: Family Policy Compliance Office, U.S. Department of Education, 400 Maryland Avenue SW, Washington, DC 20202.
© 2020 Iowa Lakes Community College. All rights reserved.
Cookie Settings
Accept All Cookies
We use cookies to enable essential services and functionality on our site, to enhance your browsing experience, to provide a better service through personalized content, and to collect data on how visitors interact with our site. To accept the use of cookies and continue on to the site, click "Accept all Cookies", or you can make changes to your cookie preferences by clicking "Cookie Settings". For more information about our use of cookies and to opt-out of cookies at any time, please refer to our website Privacy Policy.
About Your Privacy
Required Cookies
Personalization Cookies
Analytics Cookies
Marketing Cookies
Social Media / Sharing Cookies
View Our Privacy Policy
We care about data privacy, which we consider to be a fundamental human right. To that end, we adopted a series of administrative and technical procedures in order to strengthen the protection of your right to personal data protection.
Required cookies are those that are used solely for the purpose of transmitting a communication and those that are absolutely necessary for a website to provide the service that a user is requesting. Examples include an authentication cookie that identifies a user for the duration of the session once that user logs in to a website or a cookie that keeps track of items placed in an e-commerce shopping cart.
Personalization cookies are those that enable a user to access a website and receive services that are catered to that user's pre-defined characteristics, such as language, browser type used to access the service, regional configuration from where the service is accessed, etc.
Analytics cookies are those that enable the monitoring and analyzing of the behavior of users of a website. The information gathered through such cookies is used for measuring the activity of the website, platform or application and for profiling the navigation of users of the website, platform or application, in order to improve the website based on that analysis.
Marketing cookies are cookies that enable us to manage the offer of the advertising space on the web page as efficiently as possible, adapting the ad content to the content of the service requested or the use of a website.
Social Media / Sharing Cookies are third-party cookies that are used when you share information using a social media sharing button or “like” button on our website or you link your account or engage with our content on or through a social networking site such as Facebook, Twitter or YouTube. The third-party cookies procedures are managed and controlled exclusively by each provider in accordance to their own privacy policies. You can disable third-party cookies in your browser settings. In order not to be tracked by social media widgets, you can log out of all social networks you are logged in prior to visiting our website.
Close
